University of Connecticut 1998.0186
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, President's Office Records [Homer D. Babbidge, 1962-1972]
undated, 1962-1972.
1998.0186
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
145.8 Linear feet
Homer Daniels Babbidge was born in 1925 in Weston, Massachusetts, and raised in New Haven, Connecticut. He graduated from Yale University in 1945 with a degree in political science and subsequently earned his master's and doctorate from the same institution. Babbidge became president of the University of Connecticut in 1962 and remained in the office until his retirement in 1972. His years at UConn were among the most productive, and the most turbulent, in the University's history. Homer D. Babbidge died in 1984.
University of Connecticut. President's Office.
History
Homer Daniels Babbidge, Jr. was born in 1925 in West Newton, Massachusetts, and raised in New Haven, Connecticut. He graduated from Yale University in 1945 with a degree in political science, and he subsequently earned his master's and doctoral degrees from the same university. He taught in Yale's Department of American Studies for several years and then become director of Financial Aid Division. From 1955 to 1961, he served at a variety of posts in the U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, eventually becoming director of the division of higher education.
Babbidge became president of the University of Connecticut in 1962 and remained in that office until he retired in 1972. His years in office were among the most productive, and the most turbulent, in the University's history. During the Babbidge decade, the library's collection grew to over one million volumes and the University's budget quadrupled from $20 million to $80 million. The student body increased by two-thirds to 23,154, and the number of full-time employees doubled to over 4,000.
Babbidge believed that as Connecticut's only publicly supported system of higher education that had the power to grant the doctorate, the University had a special responsibility to develop the best training it could. He demonstrated this commitment to graduate education in a number of ways. The Whetten Graduate Center and the Graduate Student Residences were both built during his administration, and he initiated graduate programs in social work and materials science. By the time Babbidge retired, the number of Ph.Ds awarded by the University had tripled.
Construction on the Storrs campus and at the branches continued under President Babbidge as it had under President Jorgensen. An annex to the Wilbur Cross Library was begun in 1962, and by 1965 the University High School, E. O. Smith, and Pharmacy research wings had been completed. In 1966, an addition to the Life Science Buildings was finished and work on Physics Building continued. Work on the Farmington Health Center and The Torrington and Hartford branches also continued during the 1960s.
The University moved forward in other areas as well. The first scholarship funds for black students were approved by the Board of Trustees in 1963, and in 1968 the first Black Studies classes were conducted. A pilot honors program was established, and alumni awards for outstanding teaching and research were initiated in 1964. In 1965, plans for an art museum in the “Old Beanery” were announced. The Ford Foundation grant-funded “Semester of the Thirties”, an experimental program of total immersion in the Depression decade, was an apparent success in the fall of 1968.
The Babbidge years were also turbulent, however. During 1967 and 1968, Students for a Democratic Society ( SDS) actively demonstrated on campus against U.S. involvement in the Vietnam War. A crisis developed on 26 November 1968. Demonstrators attempted to seize control of Gulley Hall where Olin-Mathieson was conducting recruitment interviews. Violence erupted, and President Babbidge was forced to call in 200 State Police. By the 1969/1970 school year, demonstrations had slowed, and by 1970/1971, tuition had replaced Vietnam as the most pressing student issue.
To the sorrow of students and faculty alike, President Babbidge resigned in 1972. Seven thousand students, faculty, and employees signed petition asking him to stay, to no avail. In his letter of resignation, Babbidge wrote, “These have been great years for me, and it is harder than I can say to bring them to a close. But in a sense, I am keeping a promise to myself; a promise made at a time when, from an objective vantage point, I saw clearly the need to view leadership in public affairs as a relay race, in which each man in his turn passes on the baton of leadership.”
Homer D. Babbidge died in 1984.
Scope and Content
The President's Office records document the programs, politics and administration of the University of Connecticut during the presidency of Homer D. Babbidge, Jr., from 1962 to 1972.
Arrangement
The records are divided into three series.
Series I: Correspondence ( 1962-1972 ) contains correspondence between President Babbidge and campus schools, offices, institutes and faculty committees; branch campuses; trustees; external education associations and organizations; foundations, and some individual faculty members. In addition to correspondence, this series includes memoranda, reports, newsletters, minutes, and other document types. The series contains information on most campus activities and concerns of Homer Babbidge's presidency. Subjects and correspondents include: athletics, budget, building proposals, curricula and courses, W. Harrison Carter, Connecticut legislature, educational television, faculty committees, financial aid to students, Edward V. Gant, Hartford Branch, Labor Education Center, the Brien McMahon Lecture Series, Metanoia, naming of buildings, salaries, selective services, E.O. Smith High School, Student Senate, Harleigh B. Trecker, University Foundation, University Senate, as well as many others. This series is organized chronologically by academic year. Within each year the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name, organization or topic. Note that the filing is inconsistent: correspondence may be filed by an individual's name one year and by affiliated organization or department another year.
Series II: Campus Unrest ( 1968-1971 ) documents protest and activism at the University. Included is information on recruitment protests, such as Dow Chemical recruitment, the Moratorium, the Connecticut Resistance Movement ( SDS), and letters and petitions of protests and support. This series is arranged alphabetically.
Series III: Wallace Moreland ( 1964-1972 ) contains the office files of the assistant to the president. These files support Series I with additional documentation of University activities and topics such as athletics, state legislature, the Loeb award, public radio and television, student unrest, and the North-End (Hartford) project. This series is arranged in two alphabetical sequences; the second is apparently later additions to the series.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Inauguration of Dr. Homer D. Babbidge, Jr. as President of University of Connecticut (1962) and Interviews with Dr. Homer D. Babbidge, Jr., President of the University of Connecticut (1962, 1964). These materials are only available in UMatic cassettes (reformatted from 16mm film). Contact the curator for further information.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The records were transferred from the President's office in three separate accessions between 1979 and 1981.
Babbidge, Homer D.; Administrative Records.; College buildings—Connecticut.; College discipline—Connecticut.; College facilities—Connecticut.; College presidents—Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Publications.; Speeches.; Student strikes—Connecticut.; Universities and colleges—Administration.; Universities and colleges—History—20th century.; Universities.; University of Connecticut. Office of the President.; University of Connecticut—History.; University of Connecticut—Presidents.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1962-1972
  - 1962-1963
    - A (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Administrative Report (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Advisors (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - American Council on Education (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Amherst College (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Architects (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Arjona, Jaime (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - Athletics, Intercollegiate (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - Atomic Energy Commission (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - B (Box 1:, Folder 10)
    - Babbidge, Homer (Box 1:, Folder 11)
    - Board of Trustees (Box 1:, Folder 12)
    - Book File (Box 1:, Folder 13)
    - Budds, John J. (Box 1:, Folder 14)
    - Budget (Box 1:, Folder 15)
    - C (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Campus (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Capital Projects (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - Contracts (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - D (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - E (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Engineering Research Center (Box 2:, Folder 22)
    - Evans, John M. (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - Fees (Box 2:, Folder 24)
    - G (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - H (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - Harvard University (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - Health Service (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - I (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - Inauguration (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - Institute - Counseling and Guidance Training (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - J (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - K (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - L (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - Legislative Relations (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - Le (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - Legislature - Federal (Box 2:, Folder 37-39)
    - Legislature - State (Box 2:, Folder 40)
    - Legislature - State (Box 3:, Folder 41-42)
    - Liaison Committee - Board of Trustees and State Board of Education (Box 3:, Folder 43)
    - Library: James Skipper (Box 3:, Folder 44)
    - Lo (Box 3:, Folder 45)
    - M (Box 3:, Folder 46)
    - Manning, Stuart H. (Box 3:, Folder 47)
    - Maps (Box 3:, Folder 48)
    - May, Elizabeth E. (Dean, School of Home Economics) (Box 3:, Folder 49)
    - McA (Box 3:, Folder 50)
    - Me (Box 3:, Folder 51)
    - Mental Health Planning Center, State Dept. (Box 3:, Folder 52)
    - Mi (Box 3:, Folder 53)
    - Military Day (Box 3:, Folder 54)
    - Military Department (Box 4:, Folder 55)
    - Mo (Box 4:, Folder 56-57)
    - N (Box 4:, Folder 58-59)
    - Naming of Buildings (Box 4:, Folder 60)
    - National Academy of Foreign Affairs (Box 4:, Folder 61)
    - National Advisory Panel on ROTC Affairs (Box 4:, Folder 62)
    - NASU ( National Association of State Universities) (Box 4:, Folder 63)
    - National Committee on Accrediting (Box 4:, Folder 64)
    - NEA ( National Education Association) (Box 4:, Folder 65-66)
    - National Safety Council (Box 4:, Folder 67)
    - Nelson, Donald E. (Box 4:, Folder 68-69)
    - New England Board of Higher Education (Box 5:, Folder 70-73)
    - National Science Association (Box 5:, Folder 74-76)
    - New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (Box 5:, Folder 77)
    - New England Council (Box 5:, Folder 78)
    - New England Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities (Box 5:, Folder 79)
    - Norris, Robert (Dean, Continuing Education) (Box 6:, Folder 80)
    - Northby, Arwood S. (Dean of Students) (Box 6:, Folder 81)
    - Nuclear Center (Box 6:, Folder 82-84)
    - O (Box 6:, Folder 85)
    - P (Box 6:, Folder 86)
    - P1 (Box 6:, Folder 87)
    - Powers, John E. (Director of Placement) (Box 6:, Folder 88)
    - President's newsletter (Box 7:, Folder 91)
    - Public Works Department (Box 7:, Folder 92)
    - Panel on Scientific and Technical Manpower (Box 7:, Folder 93-95)
    - R (Box 7:, Folder 96)
    - Re (Box 7:, Folder 97)
    - Real Estate (Box 7:, Folder 98)
    - Recommendations (Box 7:, Folder 99)
    - Religious Education (Box 7:, Folder 100)
    - Research Corporation (Box 7:, Folder 101)
    - Research Foundation (Box 7:, Folder 102)
    - Research Grants and Contracts Projects (Box 7:, Folder 103)
    - Research Laboratory ( Ernest Kline, Supervisor) (Box 7:, Folder 104)
    - Rhodes Scholarships (Box 7:, Folder 105)
    - Rhodesia Project (Box 7:, Folder 106)
    - Ro (Box 7:, Folder 107)
    - Roberts, Thomas E. (Director of Admissions) (Box 8:, Folder 108)
    - Ryan, J. Ray (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 8:, Folder 109)
    - S (Box 8:, Folder 110)
    - Senders, William J. (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 8:, Folder 111)
    - Sch (Box 8:, Folder 112)
    - Schneller, Richard (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 8:, Folder 113)
    - Scholarships and Gifts (Box 8:, Folder 114-117)
    - Science Talent Awards (Box 8:, Folder 118)
    - Se - Sh (Box 8:, Folder 119)
    - Selective Service (Box 8:, Folder 120)
    - Sheraton Hotels (Box 8:, Folder 121)
    - Si (Box 8:, Folder 122)
    - Stamford Branch (Box 9:, Folder 123)
    - Stamford University Visiting Committee (Box 9:, Folder 124)
    - State Development Committee (Box 9:, Folder 125)
    - State Health Department (Box 9:, Folder 126)
    - State Highway department (Box 9:, Folder 127)
    - State Personnel Department (Box 9:, Folder 128)
    - State Police Department (Box 9:, Folder 129)
    - State Building Commission (Box 9:, Folder 130)
    - State Comptroller (Box 9:, Folder 131)
    - Sterling, M. Elizabeth Peterson (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 9:, Folder 132)
    - Sti (Box 9:, Folder 133)
    - Student - Administration Group (Box 9:, Folder 134)
    - Student Senate (Box 9:, Folder 135-137)
    - Student Union Board and Building (Box 9:, Folder 138)
    - Students, letters (Box 9:, Folder 139-140)
    - Su (Box 10:, Folder 141)
    - Superior Student Program (Box 10:, Folder 142)
    - T (Box 10:, Folder 143)
    - Taft School (Box 10:, Folder 144)
    - Tappan, Frances (Tech. Dir. School of Physical Therapy) (Box 10:, Folder 145)
    - Tillson Proposal (Box 10:, Folder 146)
    - To (Box 10:, Folder 147)
    - Torrington Branch (Box 10:, Folder 148)
    - Trail, John M. (Assistant Comptrollers) (Box 10:, Folder 149)
    - Trecker, Harleigh B. (Dean, School of Social Work) (Box 10:, Folder 150)
    - U (Box 10:, Folder 151)
    - Unidentified Authors (Box 10:, Folder 152)
    - University Band (Box 10:, Folder 153)
    - University Club (Box 10:, Folder 154)
    - University of Connecticu (Box 10:, Folder 155)
    - University Scholars (Box 10:, Folder 156)
    - University Security Police (Box 10:, Folder 157)
    - University Secondary School (Box 10:, Folder 158)
    - University Senate (Box 10:, Folder 159)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture (Box 10:, Folder 160)
    - U.S. Health, Education and Welfare (Box 10:, Folder 161)
    - U.S. Health, Education and Welfare (Box 11:, Folder 162-167)
    - Van Bibber, George (Director, School of Physical Education) (Box 11:, Folder 168)
    - W (Box 11:, Folder 169-170)
    - Waterbury Branch ( Patrick J. Fontaine, Sup.) (Box 11:, Folder 171)
    - Watson, Elmer S. (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 11:, Folder 172)
    - Waugh, Albert E. (Academic Vice President) (Box 11:, Folder 173-174)
    - Waugh, Albert E. (Academic Vice President) (Box 12:, Folder 175)
    - We (Box 12:, Folder 176)
    - Westover School, Middlebury, CT (Box 12:, Folder 177-178)
    - Widmer, Carolyn (Dean, School of Nursing) (Box 12:, Folder 179)
    - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation (Box 12:, Folder 180)
    - Whetten, Nathan L. (Dean, Graduate School) (Box 12:, Folder 181)
    - WHUS (Box 12:, Folder 182)
    - Wi (Box 12:, Folder 183)
    - Windham Community Memorial Hospital (Box 12:, Folder 184)
    - X, Y (Box 12:, Folder 185)
    - Yale University (Box 12:, Folder 186)
    - Yankee Conference (Box 12:, Folder 187)
    - Young, W. B. (Dean, College of Agriculture) (Box 12:, Folder 188-192)
    - Z (Box 12:, Folder 193)
  - 1963-1964
    - A (Box 13:, Folder 194-195)
    - Administrative Report (Box 13:, Folder 196)
    - Advisors (Box 13:, Folder 197)
    - African Scholarship Program (Box 13:, Folder 198)
    - Air Force (Box 13:, Folder 199)
    - Alumni (Box 13:, Folder 200-202)
    - An (Box 13:, Folder 203)
    - Association of American Colleges (Box 13:, Folder 204)
    - Association of Governing Boards of State Universities and Allied Institutions (Box 13:, Folder 205)
    - Atomic Energy Commission (Box 13:, Folder 206)
    - B (Box 13:, Folder 207)
    - Babbidge, Homer (Box 14:, Folder 208-216)
    - Babbidge, Homer (Box 14:, Folder 217-218)
    - Bailey, Clark L. (Box 14:, Folder 219)
    - Bailey, Barbara (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 14:, Folder 220)
    - Be (Box 14:, Folder 221)
    - Benton, William (Box 14:, Folder 222)
    - Bequests (Box 14:, Folder 223)
    - Bishop, Merlin D. (Box 14:, Folder 224)
    - Bo (Box 14:, Folder 225)
    - Board of Trustees (Box 14:, Folder 226)
    - Br (Box 14:, Folder 227)
    - Bro (Box 14:, Folder 228)
    - Budds, John J. (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 14:, Folder 229)
    - Budget (Box 14:, Folder 230)
    - C (Box 14:, Folder 231)
    - Campus (Box 14:, Folder 232)
    - Capital Projects (Box 14:, Folder 233)
    - Carter, W. Harrison (Dean, Arts & Science) (Box 14:, Folder 234-235)
    - Carter, W. Harrison (Dean, Arts & Science) (Box 16:, Folder 236)
    - Ce (Box 16:, Folder 237)
    - Christian, J. O. (Box 16:, Folder 238-239)
    - Civil Defense (Box 16:, Folder 240)
    - Civil Rights (Box 16:, Folder 241)
    - Clark, Hugh (Box 16:, Folder 242)
    - Co (Box 16:, Folder 243)
    - Cohen, Sumner (Box 16:, Folder 244)
    - College of the Virgin Islands (Box 16:, Folder 245)
    - College Entrance Examination Board (Box 16:, Folder 246)
    - Commencement (Box 16:, Folder 247-248)
    - Commission on Higher Education (Box 17:, Folder 249)
    - Committees
      - AD HOC Trustees - Admin - Faculty, (5/19/60) (Box 17:, Folder 250)
      - Advisory on Comprehensive Mental Health Planning (Box 17:, Folder 251-252)
      - Auditorium Advisory (Box 17:, Folder 253)
      - Foreign Student Center (Box 17:, Folder 254)
      - Exhibits (Box 17:, Folder 255)
      - Library Improvement (State) (Box 17:, Folder 256)
      - University Planning (Box 17:, Folder 257-259)
      - University Planning (Box 18:, Folder 260-262)
    - Committee - Liaison - Board of Trustees and State Board of Education (Box 18:, Folder 263)
    - Committees
      - Provost Selection (Box 18:, Folder 264)
      - Reports (Box 18:, Folder 265-268)
      - Letters (Box 18:, Folder 269)
      - Advisory of the Space Conference (Box 18:, Folder 270)
    - Computer Center (Box 18:, Folder 271)
    - Condolences (Box 18:, Folder 272)
    - Conferences (Box 18:, Folder 273)
    - Connecticut Council on Higher Education (Box 18:, Folder 274)
    - Connecticut Educational Television Corporation (Box 18:, Folder 275-276)
    - Connecticut Development Commission (Box 18:, Folder 277)
    - Connecticut Education Association (Box 18:, Folder 278)
    - Connecticut Foundation for Independent Schools (Box 18:, Folder 279)
    - Contracts (Box 18:, Folder 280)
    - Council for Financial Aid to Education (Box 18:, Folder 281)
    - Dean's Council (Box 18:, Folder 282)
    - Deans and Directors (Box 18:, Folder 283)
    - Department of Finance and Control (Box 18:, Folder 284)
    - Donahue, A. J., Jr. (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 18:, Folder 285)
    - Driscoll, Paul (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 18:, Folder 286)
    - Dunlop, John (Box 18:, Folder 287)
    - E (Box 18:, Folder 288-289)
    - Education, School of (Box 20:, Folder 290-291)
    - Education, State Department of (Box 20:, Folder 292)
    - En (Box 20:, Folder 293)
    - Engineering, School of (Box 20:, Folder 294-295)
    - Engineering Research Center (Box 20:, Folder 296)
    - Enrollments (Box 20:, Folder 297)
    - Evans, John M. (Box 20:, Folder 298)
    - F (Box 21:, Folder 299)
    - Faculty Scholarships (Box 21:, Folder 300)
    - Fees (Box 21:, Folder 301)
    - Fi (Box 21:, Folder 302)
    - Financial Aid (Box 21:, Folder 303-308)
    - Fine Arts, School of (Box 21:, Folder 309)
    - Fingles, Franklin O. (Box 21:, Folder 310)
    - Fo (Box 22:, Folder 311)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 22:, Folder 312)
    - Foreign Students (Box 22:, Folder 313)
    - Foundations (Box 22:, Folder 314)
    - Fox, Lewis (Dean, School of Dentistry) (Box 22:, Folder 315)
    - Fraternities and Sororities (Box 22:, Folder 316-317)
    - Friedmon, Don (Box 22:, Folder 318)
    - Fuller, Alfred C. (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 22:, Folder 319)
    - Games Research (Box 22:, Folder 320)
    - Ge (Box 22:, Folder 321)
    - Gill, Joseph N. (Member, Board of Trsutees) (Box 22:, Folder 322)
    - Golf Course (Box 22:, Folder 323)
    - Governor of Connecticut, John N. Dempsey (Box 22:, Folder 324)
    - Gulley Hall (Box 22:, Folder 325)
    - Gr (Box 22:, Folder 326)
    - H - Har (Box 22:, Folder 327)
    - Hartford Hospital (Box 22:, Folder 328)
    - Harvey, Robert O. (Dean, School of Business Administration) (Box 22:, Folder 329)
    - Health Service (Box 22:, Folder 330)
    - Hewitt, Harold (Dean, School of Pharmacy) (Box 23:, Folder 331)
    - Hi (Box 23:, Folder 332)
    - Holt, Guy B. (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 23:, Folder 333)
    - Honors Program (Box 23:, Folder 334)
    - Hopkins, Bert (Dean, School of Law) (Box 23:, Folder 335)
    - I (Box 23:, Folder 336)
    - Institute of
      - Cellular Biology - Hugh Clark (Box 23:, Folder 337)
      - Gerontology (Box 23:, Folder 338)
      - International Education (Box 23:, Folder 339)
      - Marine Research - John S. Rankin (Box 23:, Folder 340)
      - Nutrition and Food Service (Box 23:, Folder 341)
      - Public Service (Box 23:, Folder 342)
      - Urban Research (Box 23:, Folder 343)
    - J (Box 23:, Folder 344)
    - K (Box 23:, Folder 345)
    - Kellogg Foundation (Box 23:, Folder 346)
    - Ki (Box 23:, Folder 347)
    - Labor Education (Box 23:, Folder 348)
    - Land-Grant College Association (Box 23:, Folder 349-350)
    - Land-Grant College Association (Box 24:, Folder 351)
    - Le (Box 24:, Folder 352)
    - Legislature - Federal (Box 24:, Folder 353-354)
    - Lecture Bureau (Box 24:, Folder 355)
    - Legislature - State (Box 24:, Folder 356)
    - Library (Box 24:, Folder 357)
    - Lo (Box 24:, Folder 358)
    - Loeb Awards (Box 24:, Folder 359)
    - M (Box 24:, Folder 360)
    - McA (Box 24:, Folder 361)
    - McCormick, Joseph R. (Member, Board of Trustees) (Box 24:, Folder 362)
    - McCullough, Donald L. (Box 24:, Folder 363)
    - McMahon, Brien - Lecture Series (Box 24:, Folder 364)
    - Manning, Stuart H. (Box 24:, Folder 365)
    - Material Science Center (Box 25:, Folder 366-367)
    - May, Elizabeth E. (Dean, Home Economics) (Box 25:, Folder 368)
    - Me (Box 25:, Folder 369)
    - Medical Dental School - Mr. Wetzel (Box 25:, Folder 370-271)
    - Medical - Dental (Box 25:, Folder 372-373)
    - Mi (Box 26:, Folder 374)
    - Military Ball (Box 26:, Folder 375)
    - Military Day (Box 26:, Folder 376)
    - Mo (Box 26:, Folder 377)
    - Moreland, Wallace (Box 26:, Folder 378)
    - N (Box 26:, Folder 379-380)
    - Naming of Buildings (Box 26:, Folder 381)
    - Nathan Hale Committee ( Harry Morse, chairman) (Box 26:, Folder 382)
    - National Association of Student Personnel Administrators - Committee VIII (Box 26:, Folder 383)
    - National Education Association (Box 26:, Folder 384)
    - National Science Foundation (Box 26:, Folder 385)
    - Nelson, Don (Box 26:, Folder 386)